hardhathosting.com 2014-05-23

# Privacy Statement : Hard Hat Hosting – Managed VPS Hosting | Managed Dedicated Servers

**U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework Compliance  
**

Hardhat, Inc. complies with the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries.  Hardhat, Inc. has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement.  We will respond to your request for access to modify or delete your information within thirty (30) days. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view Hardhat, Inc.’s certification, please visit [http://www.export.gov/safeharbor](http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/ "U.S.-EU Safe Harbor")

**Other than as described in this Policy, we will not give any information about you to others without your express permission.**

**Orders for Products/Services**  
If you purchase a product or service from us, we request certain personally identifiable information from you on our order forms. You must provide contact information (such as name, email, and physical address) and financial information (such as credit card number, expiration date, and billing address).

We use this information for billing purposes and to fill your order. If we have trouble processing an order, we will use this information to contact you.

We send all new customers a welcome email to verify password and username. From time to time, we may contact you by email informing you of new products/services or special time-sensitive promotions. This form of communication provides a method to remove your email from any future communication concerning new products/services and promotions.

**Domain Registration**  
When you register a domain name through us, we must disclose your domain name and its associated Internet Protocol (“IP”) numbers to the appropriate registry in order to make your chosen domain name a functional address on the Internet. Certain registries also require that we disclose to them the names, postal addresses, telephone and fax numbers, and e-mail addresses of individuals designated as the registrant or points of contact for a given domain name. Each registry discloses certain portions (and in some cases all) of the information we are required to provide to them about your domain name registration.

**Updating Your Information**

You may alter your account information or opt out of receiving communications from us and our partners at any time. We have the following options for changing and modifying your account information or contact preferences.

1\. You may send an email to support@hardhathosting.com  
2\. You may visit your account manager by clicking login in our sites main menu.  
3\. You may send mail to Hardhat, Inc. at the following postal address:  
1627 Main St Ste 300, Kansas City, MO 64108  
4\. You may call us at: (816) 471-7688  
5\. You may fax us at (816) 303-4447

**Third Party Intermediaries**  
We use outside credit card processing companies to bill users for products and services. These companies do not retain, share, store or use personally identifiable information for any secondary purposes.

**Quote Requests**  
If you choose to submit a quote request, we will request certain personally identifiable information from you. We use this information to contact you with the requested quotation. From time to time, we may contact you by email informing you of new products/services or special time-sensitive promotions. This form of communication provides a method to remove your email from any future communication concerning new products/services and promotions.

**Contact Forms**  
If you choose to contact us using a contact form, we will request certain personally identifiable information from you. We use this information to contact you and reply to your original question or comment. If your question is sales related, we may from time to time, contact you by email informing you of new products/services or special time-sensitive promotions. This form of communication provides a method to remove your email from any future communication concerning new products/services and promotions.

**Tell-A-Friend**  
If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about our site, we will ask you for your email address and your friend’s name and email address. We will automatically send your friend(s) a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site. Hardhat, Inc. stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email and tracking the success of our referral program.

Your friend may [contact us](https://www.hardhathosting.com/customer-service/contact-us.php) to request that we remove this information from our database

**Community Forums**  
If you use a bulletin board or chat room on this site, you should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of these forums, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in these forums.

**Cookies**  
We use cookies to store visitors preferences, record session information, such as items that consumers add to their shopping cart, record user-specific information on what pages users access or visit, customize website content based on visitors’ browser type or other information that the visitor sends. Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information while on our site.

**Log Files**  
Like most standard Web servers, we use log files. These logs includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user’s movement in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses, etc. are not linked to personally identifiable information.

**Third Party Advertising**  
We do not partner with or have special relationships with any ad server companies

**Special Offers and Updates**  
If our information practices change at some time in the future we will post the policy changes to our website to notify you of these changes and provide you with the ability to opt out of these new uses. If you are concerned about how your information is used, you should check back at our Web site periodically.

**Service Announcements**  
On rare occasions it is necessary to send out a strictly service related announcement. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance we might send users an email. Generally, users may not opt-out of these communications, though they can deactivate their account. However, these communications are not promotional in nature.

**Outside Links**  
This Web site may contain links to other sites. Please be aware that we, Hardhat, Inc., are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every Web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this Web site.

**Choice/Opt-Out**  
Customers may prevent their information from being used for purposes other than those for which it was originally collected by e-mailing or writing us at the below address, or submitting your request through our helpdesk.

Upon request we provide site visitors with access to all information, including proprietary information, that we maintain about them, financial information (e.g., credit card account information) that we maintain about them, unique identifier information (e.g., customer number or password) that we maintain about them, transaction information (e.g., dates on which customers made purchases, amounts and types of purchases) that we maintain about them, communications that the consumer/visitor has directed to our site (e.g., e-mails, customer inquiries), contact information (e.g., name, address, phone number) that we maintain about them , a description of information that we maintain about them.

Consumers can access this information by contacting us, using any of the methods at the end of this statement. We will respond to your request within 14 days.

Upon request we offer visitors the ability to have inaccuracies corrected in contact information, financial information, unique identifiers, transaction information, communications that the consumer/visitor has directed to the site.

Consumers can have this information corrected by [contacting us](http://www.hardhathosting.com/customer-service/contact-us.php), using any of the methods at the end of this statement. We will respond to your request within 14 days.

**Security**  
We always use industry-standard encryption technologies when transferring and receiving consumer data exchanged with our site. We have appropriate security measures in place in our physical facilities to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of information that we have collected from you at our site.

We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you may contact us by using the below contact information.

**Legal Disclaimer**  
We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our Web site. If you feel that this site is not following its stated information policy, you may contact us by using the below contact information.

**Contact Information**  
If you have any questions regarding our privacy policy, please contact us at:  
Phone: 816-471-7688  
Email: Contact Us  
Postal Address:  
Hardhat, Inc.  
1627 Main Street, Suite 602  
Kansas City, MO 64108  
Web site URL: [http://www.hardhathosting.com](http://www.hardhathosting.com/)

Last updated: 04/18/14
